Guide to the Fernando Alegria Papers
Department of Special Collections
Fernando Alegria papers
1924-2000
1940-1998
M0651
Alegr?a, Fernando, 1918-
59 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection contains correspondence with virtually every prominent literary figure in Latin America during the mid-to-late Twentieth Century, including Pablo Neruda, Salvador Allende, Augusto Roa Bastos, Jaime Alazraki, Isabel Allende, Carlos Fuentes, Juan Rulfo, Nicanor Parra, and many others. Also includes correspondence with North American authors such as Allen Ginsberg and Lawrence Ferlinghetti, as well as Linus Pauling.The collection also contains numerous manuscripts by Alegria and other Latin American authors, including Raul Barrientos, Jorge Bernales, Alejo Carpentier, Joaquim-Francisco Coelho, Roque Dalton, Humberto Diaz-Casanueva, Juan Armando Epple, Mario Antonio Espinosa, Ricardo Israel, Reynaldo Jimenez, Luis Merino, and Pablo Neruda.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Fernando Alegria, 1989 and his son, Daniel S. Alegria, 2000.
Biography / Administrative History
Fernando Alegria, born September 16, 1918 in Santiago, Chile, to Santiago Alegria Toro and Julia Alfaro, is a poet, novelist and educator. He married Carmen Letona Melendez on Jan. 29, 1943. Together they had four children: Carmen, Daniel, Andres, and Isabel.
Alegria received his M.A. from Bowling Green State University in 1941 and his Ph.D. from University of California at Berkeley in 1947. He taught as a professor at the University of Chile, 1939; as an instructor at Bowling Green State University, 1940-1941; as an instructor, 1947-1949, as an assistant professor, 1949-1955, as an associate professor, 1955-1963, and as a professor, 1964-1967 at University of California at Berkeley; and as a professor at Stanford University from 1967-1998.
From 1970 through 1973, Alegria served as cultural attach? from the government of Salvador Allende to the United States, using his home in Berkeley, California as his base of operations in this capacity.
Alegria's organizational affiliations include the Instituto Internacional de Literature Iberoamericana; the American Association of Teachers of Spanish; and the Sociedad de Escritores.
He was a Guggenheim Fellow, 1947-1948; he won the Latin American Prize of Literature, 1943; as well as the Premio Atenea and Premio Municipal.
He published extensively; his works include Recabarren, 1938; Ideas esteticas de la poesia moderna, 1939; Ensayo sobre cinco temas de Thomas Mann, 1949; Walt Whitman en Hispanoamerica, 1954; Caballo de copas, 1957; My Horse Gonzales, 1964; Historia de la novela hispanoamericana, 1965; Genio y figura de Gabriela Mistral, 1966; Los dias contados, 1968; Los mejores cuentos de Fernando Alegria, 1968; Amerika, 1970; Coral de Guerra, 1979; El Paso de los gansos, 1980; The Chilean Spring, 1980.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains correspondence with virtually every prominent literary figure in Latin America during the mid-to-late Twentieth Century, including Pablo Neruda, Salvador Allende, Augusto Roa Bastos, Jaime Alazraki, Isabel Allende, .Carlos Fuentes, Juan Rulfo, Nicanor Parra, and many others. Also includes correspondence with North American authors such as Allen Ginsberg and Lawrence Ferlinghetti, as well as Linus Pauling.
The collection also contains numerous manuscript items as well as copies of printed works by Alegria and various Latin American authors, including Raul Barrientos, Jorge Bernales, Alejo Carpentier, Joaquim-Francisco Coelho, Roque Dalton, Humberto Diaz-Casanueva, Juan Armando Epple, Mario Antonio Espinosa, Ricardo Israel, Reynaldo Jimenez, Luis Merino, Pablo Neruda, Frederick Nunn, Roberto Quesada, Louis Marcos Rodriguez, Bernardo Subercaseaux, and Ines Villafa?e Le?n amongst others.
The collection also contains extensive subject files on notable Latin American authors, his notebooks, diaries and calendars. It also contains documentation on various international Latin American writer's conferences.
The collection also contains more than 3,000 photographs and slides of Alegria, his family, various authors and other literary figures, as well as images used in his various books.
The collection includes a series of 31 political posters from the 1960's with additional posters for readings given by Alegria from the 1970's through the 1980's, as well as performances by Chilean cultural groups, such as Inti-Illimani.
Series Description
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - Subseries A. Authors
    - Acuna Anfossi, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aguilera, Francisco (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aguilera, Marco Tulio (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Aguirre, Margarita (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Aguirre, Maria Elena [El Mercurio] (Box 1, Folder 5)
      El Mercurio
    - Alatorre, Antonio (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alazraki, Jaime (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alcala, Hugo R. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alejimenez, G. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alexander, Francisco (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Alizo, David (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Allen, Gay Wilson (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Allende, Isabel, 2 tls, 1 acs (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Allende, Maria Cecilia (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Allende, Salvador, 1 tls, 1 telegram, 1 brochure (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Allende, Tencha B. [Hortensia Bussi de], 17 tls, 3 als, 1 acs, 1 c (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Alone. Letter to Osvaldo re: Alone article re: Fernando Alegria (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Altidor, Alison (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alvarez Gardeazabal, Gustavo (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Alves Pereira, Teresinha (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Amado, Jorge (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Anderson Imbert, Enrique (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Andrade Cantero, Paola (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Andrea, Pedro (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Antoninus, Brother (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Antunez, Nemesio (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Araujo, Helena (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Arciniga, German (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Arenas, Braulio, 6 tls (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Armand, Octavio (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Arnigo, Fanny R. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Arquedas, Jose Maria (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Arraño, Alberto (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Arteche, Miguel (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Astorga, Ramon (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Atias, Guillermo (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - El autor del mono (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Ayala, Francisco (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Ayala, Juan Antonio (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Ayesa, Guillermo (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Baeza Flores, Alberto (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Baker, Shirley K. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Bardolino, Gitano (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Bareiro Saguier, Ruben (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Barquero, Efrain (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Barrientos, Raul (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Ba[rrios], Carmen (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Bellini, Giuseppe (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Benedetti, Mario (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Bernales, Jorge (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Bianco, Pepe (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Blanco, Guillermo (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Blanco, Marta (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Boero Lillo, Ernesto (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Bonnefoy, Michel (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Bourjaily, Vance (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Bracelli, Rodolfo (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Brandan, V. (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Bravo, Roberto, 1 tls (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Bravo-Elizonde, Pedro (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Brown, Guillermo (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Brunet, Marta (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Bueno, Salvador (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Caceres Milnes, Andres (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Caceres Milnes, Andres re: thesis on Fernando Alegria (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Calvo, Jorge (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Campaña, Antonio (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Campos, Javier (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Campra, Rosalba (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Camus, Albert, 1 tls (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Canas, Hernan (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Canton, Dario (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Cardenal, Ernesto (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cardona Peña, [?] (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Carnbourn Ocampo, Arturo (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Carrasco, Eduardo (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Castedo, Elena (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Castedo, Leopoldo (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Castilla, Sergio (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Castillo, J. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Castro de Moux, Maria Esther (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [Cecchi], Cesar (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cerda, Enrique (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Cerda, Julio (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Chalbaud, Roman (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Chavez Rice, Eugenio (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Christopher, George [Mayor, San Francisco] (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Coddou, Marcelo (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Concha, Jaime (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Conde, Susana (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Contreras, Raul (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Cooper, Sara E. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Cordova, Miguel L. re: Chacabuco (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cornejo Polar, Antonio (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Correa, Gustavo (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Cortazar, Julio (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Cortinez, Veronica (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Cronin, Jackie (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Cruz, Rosaura (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Cruz, Rosaura (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Danke, Jacobo (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - de [ ], Martha (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - de Aguirre, Hernando (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - de Carvalho-Neto, Paulo (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - de Cascarro, Raul Gonzalez (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - de la Barra, Pedro (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - de la Parra, Edmundo (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - de Tagle, Lillian L. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - de Vallbona, Rima (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - del [ ], Santiago (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - del Campo, Xorge (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Denevi, Marco (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - di Cassi, John (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Diaz Casanova, Humberto (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Diaz Varin, Stella (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Diezcanseco, Alfredo Pareja (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Dominguez, Nelia (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Donahue, Maraima de Semprun (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Drago, Gonzalo (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Droguet, Carlos (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Durand, Jose (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Durand, Rene (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Dussuel, Francisco (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Dyson, John P. (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Echevarria, Evelio (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Elliott, Jorge (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Endara, Julio (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Epple, Juan (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Epsztein, Lazaro Kanonich (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Epsztein, Lazaro Kanonich (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Escajadilla, Tomas (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Escudero, Alfonso M. (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Espinosa Selig, Mario (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Estrada, Julian (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 4 als, 1 tls, 3 tms, 3 cs (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Fernandez Martinez, Cesar (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - [Ferracesi], Alicia (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Fetchko, Lisa (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Fetchko, Lisa (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Finlayson, Clarence (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Flores, Arturo C. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Folsom, Ed (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Franco, Jean (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Frei Ruiz-Tagle, Eduardo [President, Chile], Alegria, Fernando. TLS to Eduardo Frei Ruiz-Tagle, 1993. Frei Ruiz-Tagle, Eduardo. TLS to Fernando Alegria, 1997. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Frias Cathalifaud, Andres Fernando (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Frois, H. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Fuensalida, Hector (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Fuentes, Carlos, 1 acs (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Fuentes, Pedro (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Furness, Edna (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Gaete, Marcelo (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Ganderats, Luis Alberto (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Garcia-Huidobro, Fernando (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Garcia Nuñez, Fernando (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Garcia Roman, Pina (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Giaconi, Claudio (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Giardinelli, Mempo (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Ginsberg, Allen, 1 acs, 1 tcs, 1 tls (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Godoy Urrutia, Cesar (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Godoy Zuniga, Maria Elena (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Goff, Brent (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Goldsack, Hugo (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Goloboff, Gerardo Mario (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Gonzalez de Cascarro, Raul (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Gonzalez Viaña, Eduardo (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Grandon, Juan Gabriel Araya (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Greaves, Carlos C. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Greenspan, Ezra (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Guerra, Lucia (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Gundelach Salinas, Roberto (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Gutierrez A., Rafael (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Gutierrez, Beningo A. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Guzman, Nicomedes (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Guzman Cruchaga, Juan (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Heine, Jorge (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Heiremans, Luis A. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Hernandez Casey, Victor (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Herrera, Armando Uribe (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Herrera, Edmundo (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Herrera, P. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Hong, Hyeran (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Hulme, Tamarya (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Ibañez Langlois, J. Miguel (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Icaza, Jorge (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Iduarte, Andres (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - [Isla Araya], Alejandro (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Izquierdo F., Gonzalo (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - [Jaimes-Freyre, Mireya ?] (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Jamison, Barbara (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Jerez, Fernando (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Jergara, Rene (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Jimenez, Gale (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Jitrik, Noe (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Jobet, Jorge (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Joseph, John F. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - K[?], Edgar C. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Kaufman, Rhoda (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Kessler, Stephen (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Knetzkoff, Eliana (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - [L?], Jaime (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - [La Molinera] (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Lado, Maria de [Aranciba?] (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Lafourcade, Enrique (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Lagmanovich, David (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Landau, David (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Lara, Omar (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - [Larcia Maignez] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Larrain, Luz (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Larrea O., Maria I. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Lars, Claudia (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Laso, Jaime (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Latcham, Ricardo (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Laughlin, J. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Lavin Cerda, Hernan (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Lazaro Carreter, Fernando (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Lazo, Waldo R. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Lee, Muna (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Lefebvre, Alfredo (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Leon, Rosario Rexach (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Lesser, Wendy (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Letelier, Isabel (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Letelier, Orlando (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Lewkowitz, Lidia F. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Lindo, Hugo (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Lonergan, Mark (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Los Autores (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Loveland, Juan (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Loyola, Hernan (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Lozano, Carlos (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Luis, Maria (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1 tls, 1 tls (photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Manns, Alejandra y Patricio (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Mansilla Torres, Sergio (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Marin, Juan (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Marinello, Juan (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Martinez Moreno, Carlos (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Martinez Toledo, Carlos (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Martre, Gonzalo (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Massis, Mahfud (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Matte Alessandri, Ester (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Mayer, Frances (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - McClure, Michael, 1 tcs (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - McMillen, Robert A. (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Mellac, Regine (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Mendoza Careaga, Rosaura (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Menendez Leal, Alvaro (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Meza Fuentes, Roberto (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Millan, Maria (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Millas, Jorge (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Mistral, Gabriela, 10 acs, 1 als (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Mixco Fisschnaler, Jose re: Fernando Alegria's apartment in El Parque Forestal (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Molina, Maria Teresa del Canto (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Moncada, Julio (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Mondragon, Sergio (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Moneta, Carlos Juan (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Monteforte Toledo, Mario (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Monterde, Francisco (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Montesinos, Cristian (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Morand, Carlos (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Moreno, Martin (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Morley, S.G. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mortheiru, Pedro (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Muñoz Valenzuela, Diego (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Musso, Osvaldo Rodriguez See: Rodriguez Musso, Osvaldo (Box 5, Fol. 65) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Negro, Adele (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Neruda, Pablo, 1 als, 1 tls (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Nuñez, Fernando Garcia (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Nuñez del Prado, Marina (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Ocampo Heredia, Maria Luisa (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Oddo, Willie (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Odio, Eunice (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Olano Campo, Nora (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Olguin, Manuel (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Onis, Jose de (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Orrego, Ramon Zañartu. See Zañartu Orrego, Ramon (Box 7, Fol. 30) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Orrellana, Carlos (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Ortega, Cecilia de (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Ortega, Julio (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Ortega, Matilde de (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Ortiz, Adalberto (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Orton, Juan and Kelly (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Osorio, Luisa Kroger de (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Osorio, Nelson (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Osorio S., Gustavo (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Otayza Carrazola, Fernando (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Otero, Lisandro (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Palazuelos, Juan-Augustin (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Paredes, Jose O. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Pareja Diezcanseco, Alfredo (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Parra, Angel, 1 als (photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Parra, Esthras (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Parra, Nicanor, 10 als (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Pauling, Linus, 2 tls, 1 als (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Paull, Laura (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Pazurkiewicz, Stanislaus (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Pearson, Lon (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Peccorini, Francisco (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Pena, Richard (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Pereira, Teresinka (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Perezdiaz, Roberto (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Pina, Juan Andres (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Pino, Miriam (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Pinto, Gabriela Nunez (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Pizarro, Andres (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Poblete Vara, Hernan (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Poletti, Syria (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Pulido, Theresa (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Quezada, Jaime (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Quilapayun (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Quirroz, Alberto (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Radrigan, Juan (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Rama, Angel (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Rebolledo S., Enrique M. (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Rencoret, David (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Rencoret Donoso, Rodolfo (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Rieloff, Paulina (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Riveros Aedo, Jaime (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Roa, Amelia de (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Roa Bastos, Augusto (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Robinson, Marc (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Robles, Martha (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Rodriguez, Louis M. (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Rodriguez Musso, Osvaldo (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Rodriguez-Alcala, Hugo (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Rodriguez Arenas, Aniceto (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Rodriguez Monino, A. (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Roggiano, Alfredo A. (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Rojas, Gonzalo (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Rojas, Gonzalo (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Rojas, Manuel (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Rojas Murphy, Andres (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Rokha, Winnet de (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Romo, Eugenio Matus (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Rossel, Milton (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Ruiz M., Rafael (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Rulfo, Juan (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - S, Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Sabato, Ernesto (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Sabato, Matilde de (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Sabella, Andres (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Sainz de Robles, Federico Carlos (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Salas, Horacio (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - San Martin, Hernan (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Sanchez, Luis Alberto (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Sanchez Hernandez, Fidel (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Santamaria, Haydee (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Santini, Adrian (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Schwartz, Kessel (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Schwartz, Perla (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Schwarz, Egon (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Seeger, Pete (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Seoane, Manuel (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - [Serrano?], Miguel (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - [Silva, C.?] (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Silva, Ricardo (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Silva Acevedo, Manuel (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Silva Castro, Maria (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Silva Castro, Raul (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Silva Herzog, Jesus (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Silva M., Constancio (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Simon E., Raul (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Singleton (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Skarmeta, Antonio, 4 tls, 1 tcs (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Slavinsky, Barbara A. (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Smid, Zdanek (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Soria, Antonio (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Soto, F. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Soto S., Helvio (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Souper, Eliana (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Spaulding, Robert K. (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Stanchi Nahuel, Hugo (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Stein, Margarita (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Stokes, Lisa (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Subercaseaux, Bernardo (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Subercaseaux, Elizabeth (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Sucre, Guillermo (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Surco, Sara & Marcelo (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Tellez, Eugenio (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Thayer, Alicia (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Thiebes, Richard (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Tienken, Arthur (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Tomic, Radomiro (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Toral, Mario (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Torres A., Osvaldo (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Torres Lozano, Jorge (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Torres Rioseco, Arturo (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Toruno, Juan Felipe (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Traupe, Quincy (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Trujillo, Carlos A. (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Turet, David (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - [Turino?], Pepita (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Undurraga, Antonio de (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Uribe Herrera, Armando (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Ur[ ]de, Paul (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - V[ ], Mercedes (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Valdes, Natasha (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Valdiviano, Jaime (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Valenzuela, Victor M. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Vallarino d'Alfonso, Silvio (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Vallbona, Rima de (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Vargas Llosa, Mario, 3 tls, 1 broadside (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Vasquez de Assor, Martha (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Velasquez Mackenzie, Jorge (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Venegas, Sergio Bueno (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Verbitsky, Bernardo (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Vergara, Rene (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Verissimo, Erico (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Viaña, Jose Miguel (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Vientos Gaston, Nilita (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Viereck Salinas, Edgardo (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Viñas, David (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Vodanovic, Sergio (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Volek, Emil (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Walpole, Ronald N. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Weber Schaeffer, Blanche (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Welz, Ursula (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Whelan, Vincent Patrick (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Witker, Alejandro (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Wolff, Egon (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Xirau, Ramon (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Young, Alejandro (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Yurkievich, Saul (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Zalamea, Luis (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Zañartu Orrego, Ramon (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Zavaleta, Carlos-Eduardo (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Zondek, Veronica (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Zurita, Raul (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - [Unidentified], Alastair [The New Yorker] (Box 7, Folder 34)
      The New Yorker
    - [Unidentified], Alejandra (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - [Unidentified], Alfonso (Box 7, Folder 36)